Patrick Best

Greater Richmond Region



patrickbest1991@gmail.com



inkedin.com/in/patrick-best-784aa54a

Summary

Patrick Best is a Senior API Engineer at Snagajob, and previusly worked as a Software Engineer for Tech Dynamism. He has a broad area of experience in Information Technology (IT) ranging from business analysis and project management to programming. He is also a newly minted Twilio Champion! You can read more about the Twilio Champion program here: https://www.twilio.com/champions.

As graduate of the Computer Information Systems (CIS) Major and a Music Industry (MUI) minor from James Madison University, Patrick received formal educational training in business and IT strategies.

Patrick Best has technical experience including:

Technical Skills:

- Programming: C#, .Net Core, RabbitMQ, Web API, Node, Javascript
- Database Design: MYSQL and MongoDB
- Source Control: Git, GitHub
- Systems Analysis and Design: SDLC, Scrum, and Feasibility Analysis
- Business Process Modeling: UML Activity Design and Visio
- Server Administration: Linux and Putty
- Cloud Infrastructure: Basic AWS knowledge

Patrick was also a member of the electronic duo, Modus Culture, and plays several musical instruments including guitar, bass, drums, and piano.

Experience



S Senior Software Engineer

Snagajob

Jul 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months +)

S Software Engineer

Snagajob

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 (11 months)

Software Engineer

Tech Dynamism

Jan 2015 - Jan 2019 (4 years 1 month)

Participated in all aspects of the software development process, from architecture and design to implementation, coding, and testing (Full Stack). Responsible for writing code interfaces, data flows, application availability, and documentation. Assisted in performing on-site client work.

- # Performed product design, bug verification, release testing, and beta supported projects
- # Supported, maintained and documented software functionality
- # Maintained standards compliance
- # Saw projects / assignments through to completion while adhering to business timelines
- # Improved upon current skills while also developing and mastering new technical skills
- # Provided 3rd level support to all applications
- # Ensured proper documentation is maintained on all projects
- # Worked independently on external client projects by creating business process documentation, implementing technical structures from that documentation, and consulting for technical best practices

Gromobi Junior Team Leader

GroMobi

Feb 2014 - Dec 2014 (11 months)

- # Conducted Human Resources management through application review and interviews
- # Produced written content through White Papers and Blogs
- # Administered Project Management of business development teams of four (4)
- # Generated leads through RFP and RFQ research
- # Mapped and documented processes and functionality of mobile applications
- # Innovated internal operations and processes through learned practices

aramark Dining Services Student Supervisor

Aramark

Sep 2013 - Aug 2014 (1 year)

- # Managed student teams within specialized shops
- # Obtained significant customer service experience

Production Intern

NTelos Wireless Pavilion

Apr 2013 - Sep 2013 (6 months)

- # Maintained a strict timetable for the performance venue
- # Operated stage sound and lighting

📃 Legal Intern

Burke and Kilduff P.C.

Jun 2011 - Aug 2011 (3 months)

- # Oversaw title searching of local properties
- # Organizational and Administrative office skills

Wellness Center Staff

YMCA of the USA (National Resource Office)

Jan 2010 - Aug 2011 (1 year 8 months)

Created user profiles and taught program functionality of ActivTrax

Built and maintained customer relationships

CHHS 30 Day Extern

University of Maryland Center for Health and Homeland Security Jul 2010 - Jul 2010 (1 month) # Tabletop Experience at the Baltimore Ravens Stadium # Legal Research Experience



🤼 Service Associate

Food Lion

Aug 2008 - Feb 2010 (1 year 7 months)

- Assisted in Customer Service
- Worked the Cash Register
- Bagged Groceries

Education



James Madison University

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Computer Information Systems 2009 - 2014

Skills

Time Management • PowerPoint • Microsoft Word • SQL • C# • Customer Service • Microsoft Excel • JavaScript • Java • AngularJS

Honors & Awards



3rd Place in the Hack to Impact Competition for the Wounded Warriors - Deloitte Mar 2014

The Deloitte Hack to Impact (H2I) Competition requires student teams to use technology to drive social change. This competition has been created to demonstrate real-life business technology problems that consultants face on a daily basis. Deloitte Consulting professionals assist clients with challenges that may be solved through effective solution design and development, project planning, and presentation. The competition serves as an opportunity for student teams to develop these skills and have some fun in the process. In addition to supporting our Federal Government and commercial clients, Deloitte Consulting regularly serves non-profit clients and other organizations through pro bono efforts. The purpose of this competition is to provide teams with a similar opportunity to use technical and functional expertise to create and add real value to real people.